E: hello@jamiethe.dev

Jamie Peutherer

Front-End Web Developer (React)

jamiethe.dev | github.com/xnanga

ABOUT ME

Self-taught front-end developer confident using React to build performant web apps. I'm eager for a professional role to build on my skills, learn from a forward-looking employer, and contribute to a growing codebase.

I have a strong background in technical Search Engine Optimisation which gives me an edge in ensuring web products perform well in Google Search. My experience working in both agency and in-house roles means I am adaptive, used to continual learning, and meeting stakeholder requirements.

WEB DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

Yu-Gi-Oh! Deckbuilder — A trading card deckbuilding web app

React, Zipcelx | GitHub Repo | Live Demo

Uses the Yu-Gi-Oh! API to allow users to search, filter, and sort all cards in the Yu-Gi-Oh! trading card game, then build a full deck which can then be exported to a handy XLSX file.

This was an ideal project to increase my confidence working with REST APIs and manipulating relatively complex React state critical to rendering a web app's UI.

Linfolio — A lite recreation of the Ubuntu Linux

React, React-Draggable, EmailJS | GitHub Repo | Live Demo

Created to display key information in modals that mimic the design of the Ubuntu Linux operating system. I used this SPA to showcase my portfolio at jamiethe.dev.

This project allowed me to practice React fundamentals, create forms with validation, and experiment with a drag and drop library.

Listo — A kan-ban style productivity web app

JavaScript | GitHub Repo | Live Demo

Inspired by Trello, I wanted to create a kan-ban style board focused more on the solo worker. It allows users to create, update, and delete lists and cards, add due dates and priority levels, and see approaching due tasks in a task timeline.

Listo was a great opportunity to try taking an OOP approach to JavaScript and to work with larger datasets. I also took the opportunity to get more comfortable using Local Storage.

PropertySearchr — A modern business website homepage

JavaScript, Intersection Observer API | GitHub Repo | Live Demo

A fully-responsive homepage for a fictional property website; it features many common components used on modern webpages. These include image sliders, card carousels, tabular content, and responsive navigation.

I wanted to improve my DOM manipulation and styling abilities, so I created these key components manually as a challenge. This was also a good opportunity to experiment with the Intersection Observer API.

LANGUAGES & FRAMEWORKS

- JavaScript (ES6+)
- React
- CSS3 / SASS
- HTML5 / JSX

KEY SKILLS & KNOWLEDGE

- Good understanding of industry tools: NPM,
 Git, & Github.
- CMS Experience with WordPress, Magento, & BigCommerce.
- Comfortable with data: Google Analytics, Tag Manager, Optimize; also Hotjar & CrazyEgg.
- * 7+ years of SEO/digital experience across both agency & in-house roles.
- Proficient with web tools including Screaming Frog, SEMrush, Lighthouse, Chrome Dev Tools & Ahrefs.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Scottish Qualifications Authority — Digital Officer

August 2021 - Present

Wearing both a webmaster and SEO lead's hat, I am a part of an Agile digital team that manages the SQA's 15,000+ page website and I spearhead the organisation's SEO campaign.

Key Responsibilities

- Plan and manage SQA's SEO campaign to increase organic traffic and ensure the website meets user needs.
- Provide experience-backed and data-driven SEO advice to stakeholders across the company.
- Handle requests from stakeholders for website updates and improvements including site speed, publications, page structure/styling, and implementing forms.
- Provide training and best practice to staff on SEO and web best practice.

Boyd Digital — SEO Manager

January 2017 - August 2021

Leading a team of SEO executives reporting to the Head of SEO, I was responsible for the KPI growth of my own assigned clients while ensuring the team is driving client campaigns forward in their day-to-day activities.

Key Responsibilities

- Create and carry out long-term digital marketing campaigns for over 30+ clients in a wide range of different industries & markets.
- Manage, maintain, and update client websites as necessary; experience with WordPress, Magento, BigCommerce, Shopify, Joomla, Umbraco, and various bespoke CMSs.
- Draft technical and strategic business documentation for web developers, clients, external marketing directors, and company owners.
- Extensive use of data-driven tools such as Google Analytics, Tag Manager, Accuranker, and Ahrefs to report KPIs, traffic projections, and website conversions.

Key Achievements

- Led a website migration for one of the UK's largest radiator retailers after they had lost rankings and visibility following the June 2019 Google Core Algorithm update. They then regularly doubled their organic traffic and revenue in year-on-year comparisons.
- Noted the rising interest in cryptocurrency searches and created an optimised "cryptocurrency lawyer" page on a client's website. This became their highest traffic-driving page for several months, outperforming their homepage and yielding an overall increase in organic traffic and generated leads.

EDUCATION

Glasgow Caledonian University — BSc Psychology (Hons) 1st Class

September 2012 - August 2016

Covered a range of topics and schools of practice on human thought and behaviour. I also authored a dissertation concerning personality and its relationship with Just World Theory.

REFERENCES

Available on request.